# John Flood

<u>iflood215@gmail.com</u>
802-309-0753
Indianapolis, IN
<a href="https://jflood215.github.io">https://jflood215.github.io</a> - Portfolio
https://www.linkedin.com/in/john-flood-developer - LinkedIn

# **Objective**

Dietitian turned developer, looking to utilize an eagerness to learn and a passion for coding to transition into a developer or engineer role. I have 10+ years of experience collaborating and communicating on successful teams and look to bring my drive and motivation to this new career.

### **Education**

# **Eleven Fifty Academy**

Full Stack Web Development Program

May 2020 - Oct. 2020

24-week immersive learning program for Web Development taught with industry-guided curriculum, real-world project based learning, and 500+ hours of logged coding time and training.

## **SUNY Plattsburgh**

Bachelors of Science in Nutrition, with a minor in chemistry

#### **Technical Skills**

Experienced: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Git

Knowledgeable: TypeScript, Node.js, SQL, Python, APIs, JSON, Express, Bootstrap, Material UI, Redux

# **Technical Projects**

- Full Stack calorie calculator and recipe API using React for the front end along with Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL for the back end. <a href="https://macro-recipe-weight-client.herokuapp.com">https://macro-recipe-weight-client.herokuapp.com</a>
- Created a responsive website portfolio using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap to showcase my skills to friends, family, and employers. <a href="https://jflood215.github.io">https://jflood215.github.io</a>
- A React project utilizing the New York Times API, Bootstrap, and custom CSS that allows searching all NYT articles by subject and date span. https://nyt-react-api.web.app

# **Professional Experience**

### Noom Inc.

# Front End Intern/Volunteer

Dec. 2020 – Jan. 2021

- Gained experience with Git, Redux, and React, in collaboration with the engineering team.
- Created an FAQ accordion drop down with JavaScript, React and Redux for the Noom website.
- The FAQ component was able to improve CVR by 4% and determine most relevant Q & A.

# Noom Inc.

#### Virtual Health Coach

July 2019 – Current

- Met and exceeded all expectations even as company growth exceeded 200% this year.
- Exceptional marks on all performance and transcript reviews.
- Managed a high caseload consistently and efficiently from enrollment to completion.

#### Lincare

#### Senior Medical Nutrition Specialist

Feb. 2009 – July 2019

- Worked as part of the highest grossing, and most successful enteral office in the company.
- Supported and managed multiple dietitians and offices in 6 states around the Midwest.
- Trained over 100 new dietitian hires on all clinical and insurance related aspects of the job.